This area will provide a focus for research and innovation in areas related to security systems and forensic investigation and will build upon the national and international standing of the existing expertise in these fields at the University of Canberra. It will bring together key researchers from across all three Divisions of the University, link with existing areas of research strength from the different disciplines at the University of Canberra and partner with external organisations related to this field. This Centre will address key issues and extend the potential outcomes within this important field through bringing together a multi-disciplinary group of researchers and professionals who will work closely with government, industry and the professions to achieve the stated outcomes

To be a nationally and internationally recognised Centre of Excellence in research that is proactive in providing comprehensive and integrated multi-disciplinary solutions to issues confronting the Security and Forensic fields and that attracts innovative collaborations with industry and professionals that have outcomes that are of direct benefit to the national and international communities

To develop a comprehensive approach to research focused on improving security across a range of areas that will have novel, integrated and synergistic outcomes in the areas of information sciences, cryptology, electronic systems and e-crime, border protection and customs, and biological systems, including the environment, animal and human health.
To identify and coordinate innovative research programs in both security and forensic fields that engage the industry sector and provide synergistic industry-linked research collaborations and post-graduate student programs;
To be proactive in identifying areas requiring strategic advancement of knowledge in and solutions to new and existing security threats and forensic assessments and disseminate the outcomes for implementation within the relevant public or private industry sectors; and
To provide actual and future benefits in the security and forensic fields through active engagement of the legal and policy specialists that will result in a reduction in crime through improved evidence analysis for conviction and prevention systems.

These goals will be measured by the outcomes and outputs resulting from the research and the utilisation of these within the industry and professional sector, the influence they have on society, on affecting policy and through the measurable benefit they provide to law enforcement and legal procedure

The last decade has witnessed major changes to both our national security requirements and in the patterns of human conflict.  Consequently, governments demand integrated, coordinated and cost-effective solutions for responding to a broadened threat spectrum. There is a clear need for similar Security and Forensic research facilitation in Australia. This Centre is unique in that it is designed to deal with a broader interdisciplinary analysis of Australia's Security and Forensic needs and takes a more global strategic approach to the important issues. The proposed Centre aims to identify and facilitate research programs that will enhance the security and safety of Australians through improved awareness, integration and coordination of existing resources and strategies for the development of policies, capabilities and procedures for Australia’s protection and fight against crime.

This Centre will bring together a unique combination of professional researchers and end-users in the forensic disciplines; information sciences, biometrics and secure communications; medical, health and environmental sciences; law enforcement, customs and border protection; e-security, decoding and fraud; public sector governance and management; law and evidence; and social and economic modelling.  The Centre will establish essential and unique links between these groups to enable research, policy, and operational synergies that would not otherwise occur.  Together, they will advance national and international security research and develop innovative options for better anticipation and management of potentially serious threats to the health, wellbeing and security of Australians. Additional benefits of the Centre’s research are flow-on consequences for cross-portfolio cooperation and with outcomes that have the potential to advise and guide government and industry.

Security research today focuses on maintaining the viability and protecting various systems from threat and depends upon the contribution of many disciplines working together to ensure that a system is in place that considers all relevant factors.  Protection occurs at a number of strategic levels and includes understanding the nature of a threat, preparation for a possible threat, prevention of the consequences of a threat, response to the consequences of a threat, and recovery from the consequences of a threat. In addressing these strategic levels, it is essential to integrate research that addresses the forensic and legal issues to enable effective  response and recovery. Security threats may be unintentional, accidental and unorganised, or they may be deliberate, organised and malicious (including  criminal and terrorist activities).  While the latter threats occupy much current media discussion, the former class of security threats can have significant devastating social, environmental and economic consequences. As an example, it is now estimated that identity theft is costing Australia in excess of $1.2 billion per annum through credit card, bank account, social security and other such fraudulent theft.

At the University of Canberra we have academics, research staff and students with the expertise, discipline base, resources, collaborative links and research profile to achieve the goals of this Area of Research Strength. This Centre is unique in that it is an integrated "across university" multi-disciplinary Area of Research Strength focusing on the National Research Priority of Safeguarding Australia. Our national capital location also makes us a "natural" to play a networking and linkages role bringing together researchers, professions, industry and government for developing programs and achieving outcomes that respond to national priorities. In addition to our specialised resources, UC also possesses certain infrastructure (eg. electronic courtroom, ISO standard laboratories, etc) that provides us with a unique competitive advantage compared to other universities

The Diploma in Languages is available to all enrolled undergraduate students of the University. This Diploma allows students to complete a three-year sequence in a foreign language while maintaining the requirements for their chosen degree. It is available to beginner students and to students with previous knowledge of the language at a Continuing and Intermediate-Advanced levels (see separate entries). Students enrol in their chosen language at each year level and are normally expected to enrol in less than a full-time load in their degree units for that year. This process will extend the period required to complete both programs to a minimum of four years. Students can start the Diploma units in first or second year of their undergraduate degree. Students starting the Diploma in their third year of undergraduate study can graduate from their degree and finished the remaining Diploma units on a part time basis. 

This Diploma allows students to develop language skills and cultural competence in Chinese, Japanese or Spanish, adding value to and internationalising their degree. Students will acquire language skills that can be used within their professional careers furthering their employment opportunities in Australia or overseas. By the end of the course at the Beginning Level, students will have acquired an intermediate level of communicative skills and cultural competence in their chosen language

A full-time student would normally study four units in each of three semesters, but may extend the course to two years by studying three units per semester. A part-time student would normally study two units per semester. In the first semester, students must take Professional Practice G. The remaining three units may be chosen from a variety of units at graduate (G) or postgraduate (PG) level in the areas of programming, systems analysis and design, computer networks and project and quality management. G level units would normally be selected to satisfy any prerequisites for PG level units to be taken in semesters 2 and 3.

In the second and third semesters, students take PG level units in areas that interest them. The PG level units currently on offer are listed below, grouped by specialisation. Units with an asterisk (*) have a prerequisite of 2 years’ work experience. Please note that in any one year, only a selection of these units will run.
In addition to the list below, individual project units, and (for students specialising in Business Informatics) an internship are available

News acronyms are acronyms of frases used in news writing. They are mostly composed of the first letters of the words in the frase and are best to be written in upper case. The frases are generally in english although some may be in native languages. 

